Hi, guys. Surprise, surprise. This not-quite-widely-advertised meeting was such a fun surprise for me,
but I did leave work early and drive up here from L.A., so thank you for giving me my three minutes.
Hello and welcome, everybody, to the first known-as-government here in California City.
On a personal note, what the actual heck are we doing?
The last time I had been here, this wasn't a city that I had much faith in economically,
but this seems to be something that is growing larger and larger of a problem.
So what I heard first was that CoreCivic was coming in because they were going to be a boon to the city,
and that would save all the residents.
But now, regardless of the new and illegal business that is supposedly profiting, you guys,
you are still raising rates on local residents.
So what I'm saying here is no matter what this city does,
it's not able to meet its financial obligations or its commitments to its citizens.
Now, we all know that the reason that I'm standing here is obviously immigration,
but I respect the fact that this is not an open-common section, so I will tie it into the fact.
The finances here are so messy in so many ways that I do not understand how you would think
that adding that additional indignity of housing a concentration camp,
because let's be clear, that's what that business is, that unregulated, un-so-far-investigated,
and to my mind, inhumane business that is supposed to bring profits to the city
and supplement the low-income residents that live here.
Yet, mind-bogglingly, even though you have gotten in bed with Satan himself,
your residents are still struggling and coming to you.
Through rain and through unannounced expectation of presence,
everybody shows up here.
Do you know what I had to go through to get a babysitter to be here right now from L.A.?
I am sick of this business.
This is not working.
I don't care anymore.
I'm not going to beg you to do the decent thing.
If you won't do it for people who aren't residents, who are what?
Illegal?
Because let's be so clear, immigration is a civil issue, like getting a ticket or tagging.
Not a criminal issue.
What your city is doing is housing people here illegally in a for-profit prison,
supposedly to offset the cost to let your residence lives get better.
Nobody's life is better.
Is anybody in this room saving money?
They're not.
I would have heard it, right?
So I got in the car, got a babysitter, got off work, really drove up here.
Because guess what?
Last time I spoke, a girl was here, Ria Khan, and she told you that her mother,
Masuma, was right down the road.
And Masuma is out.
And I've had the glorious opportunity to sit with her and her family.
A real woman whose daughter came here and spoke to you is out.
And I'm going to sit down with her again tomorrow because her story is sacred and deserves to be heard.
And I will keep coming back because I will keep my word.
Even if you don't, I will keep showing up.
As a voice for people who do not have one moment of time for life lost to the horseback.
Boo.
Thank you.